ourabh Kumar

🛘 (+91) 9110086006 | 🔀 kumarsourabh556@gmail.com | 🌴 sourabhbit.github.io | 🗗 sourabhbit | 🖹 sourabh-kumar | 🛅 sourabhbit | 🜬 kumarsourabh556

Summary _

Passionate front-end developer with 2 years of experience using JavaScript, HTML5, SCSS, CSS to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for client-facing landing pages. Specializes in using ReactJs, Redux-Saga, Styled Component and Unit Testing using Jest and Enzyme. Currently learning and implementing Micro-Front end in Lenskart.com

Work Experience _____

Lenskart. Bangalore, India

TECH@LENSKART - FRONTEND DEVELOPER

October. 2021 - Present

- Working as a Front End developer on product Lenskart Web UI which is developed using ReactJs and Javascript Technologies.
- Developed Voting system for ZeeTv SaReGaMaPa. https://srgmp.lenskart.com/vote
- Implemented apply coupon features on Lenskart M-site
- Developing Micro Frontend architecture.

Datametica. Pune, India

MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF

Sep. 2020 - Oct, 2021

- · Working as a Front End developer for the product Flamingo which is developed using ReactJs and Javascript Technologies.
- Developed License management architechture for product activation.
- Handled all the client-side validation using JavaScript with HTML and CSS for design.
- Doing Unit Testing using JEST and Enzyme.
- · Managing newly joined members as Buddy Mentor and assisting with client assessment team members if they get stuck anywhere.

Smartserv. Pune India

TECHNICAL ASSOCIATE

- Built email delievery pipeline to reduce Bounce and Complaint Rate.
- Worked in revamping of Sales Tax Module Architecture
- Deployed a centralized Notification System for Web CRM and Web Android CRM.

BizAugmentor Global Services Pvt Ltd, India

Delhi, India

May. 2019 - July. 2019

Jan. 2020 - July. 2020

• Worked on Income Tax Return E-filing Web Application Project.

Swathi High School. Hyderabad, India

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

Aug. 2018 - Nov. 2018

- Developed website for school swathihighschool.com.
- Built Admin Panel to maintain registration of new batch.

Atlancey Cloudtech Pvt Ltd.

Noida, India

FREELANCE FRONT END DEVELOPER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

- Jun. 2017, Nov. 2018 • Developed Class 12th Physics Hindi App using Web Activity and Adobe Muse.
- Developed Some Websites using HTML, CSS, JS and PHP.

Project

INDUSTRY PROJECTS

Lenskart Home Try On

Lenskart HTO

MODULE LEAD

- Worked on revamping of Lenskart HTO using latest technologies.
- Tech Stack NextJs, ReactJs, Redux-Toolkit, Styled Component, RESTApi Integration

ZeeTv-SaReGaMaPa Lenskart - SRGMP

- Worked as project frontend lead for the development of voting portal for ZeeTV SaReGaMaPa.
- Tech Stack Js, ReactJs, Redux-Toolkit, Styled Component, RESTApi Integration

License Management Datametica

MODULE LEAD

· Worked as Module lead for development of License management architecture and implementation in all products of Datametica

• Tech Stack - Js, VueJs, ReactJs, REST

Correction of the email bounce and delivery pipeline on the SmartServ platform.

Smartsery

MODULE DEVELOPER

 Developed an application to track email whether it is delivered to the another person whether it is got bounced or whether the person complaint for the email..

Tech Stack - AWS, NodeJS 12.x, MongoDB

Sketch Feature on SmartServ Android Application.

Smartserv

MODULE DEVELOPER

Smartserv Web Android

· Build a feature to make sketch on whiteboard and sketch can also be drawn on clicked pictures from camera and mark it with shapes or free lines and save as notes.

- Tech Stack ReactJs, NodeJs
- npm react-html5-camera-photo

Push Notification feature on SmartServ Android App and Web CRM.

Smartsery

MODULE DEVELOPER

Smartserv Web Android

- Build a feature to send 30 min prior Job Notification to Technician and send Notification to Service Manager if Technician miss the job.
- Tech Stack ReactJs, NodeJs, RESTApis, Parse
- **npm** web-push

Class 12th Physics Hindi Android App

Class 12th Physics Hindi Android App

Atlancey

· Worked as UI Engineer in developing India's first complete hindi Class XII physics app

Skills_

Front-end ReactJS, VueJs, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, Material-UI

Library Redux-Saga, Lodash and Underscore, d3.js, AntD

Unit Testing Jest, Enzyme

Back-end PHP Database MySQL

> Others OOPs, Ajax, Git, GitHub, RestAPI, SDLC, Jira

Programming Js, Node.js

> OS Windows, Macintosh, Linux

Languages Hindi, English

Education

Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra

Ranchi, India

B.E. IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Aug. 2016 - May. 2020

DAV Public School, Sec-IV

Bokaro, India

ALL INDIA SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION

Jun. 2013 - April. 2015

DAV Public School Barora, Jharkhand, India

ALL INDIA SECONDARY SCHOOL EXAMINATION May. 2013

Achievements

Rising Star Award, Appreciated with Rising Star Award in Datametica 2021

Datametica, Pune

2018 Contingent winner, E-Summit 2018 orgainsed by Entrepreneurship Development Cell, BIT Mesra BIT Mesra, India

2017 Scholarship, Google FrontEnd Scholarship - Udacity

Winner, Stock-Exchange Event College Fest 2017 BIT Mesra

Interests_

- * Travelling,
- * Volunteering,